Finding Aid for the Oliver Cromwell Carmichael Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Biographical/Personal
  - Biographical/Personal Material
    - Articles on OCC in University of Alabama Alumni News, Vol.36, no.3, July 1954; July – August 1956 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Press release – Announcement of Resignation as President of University of Alabama, November 5, 1956 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Man of the South – Election of 1956 – OCC a nominee (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Biographical information (Oliver C. Carmichael, Jr.) (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Asheville, North Carolina (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Biltmore Forest Country Club (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Notebook (1) (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Notebook (2) (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Notebook (3) (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - Notebook (4) (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - Notebook (5) (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Biographical/Personal Material
    - Notebook (6) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Notebook (7) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Notebook (8) (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Notebook (9) (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Invitations (1) (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Invitations (2) (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Invitations (3) (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Invitations (4) (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Invitations (5) (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Invitations (6) (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Invitations (7) (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Occasional cards (1) (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Occasional cards (2) (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Occasional cards (3) (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Occasional cards (4) (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Photographs
    - Photographs (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Photographs (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Academic/Professional Career - Rhodes Scholar
    - Rhodes Scholar, Wadham College, Oxford University, 1912-1913 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Rhodes Scholars, class of, 1913 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Rhodes Scholars, Wadham College Society, 1963 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Rhodes Scholarship Trust, 1933-1958 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Rhodes Scholarship Trust, 1959–1960 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Rhodes Scholarship Trust, 1961–1965 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Rhodes Scholars – Bodleian Library Fund (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Rhodes Scholars – American Oxonian, 1948; 1959 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Rhodes Scholars – Publications (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Rhodes Scholars – Miscellany – articles, invitations, etc. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Academic/ Professional Career – Kappa Delta Pi Honor Society in Education
    - Kappa Delta Pi papers (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Academic/Professional Career – Phi Beta Kappa Honor Society
    - 1957–1959 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - 1960–1961 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - 1962–1965 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Invitations, 1961–1966 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Academic/Professional Career – Alabama College, President
    - Correspondence, programs, addresses (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Programs, 1929–1965 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Research notes for speeches (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Academic/Professional Career – Vanderbilt University, 1935–1946
    - Chancellor, Letters of congratulations, 1937–1938; 1945 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Chancellor, inauguration – a volume of greetings from institutions containing letters, photographs, and newspaper clippings, September 21, 1937 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Chancellor, inauguration – programs and other material, February 3-5, 1938 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Chancellor, inaugural celebrations – program, February 3-5, 1938 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Programs, 1896-1908 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - University administration correspondence, 1910-1918 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - 1935–1962 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - program – address at Institute of Public Affairs, University of Virginia, 1939 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Programs, directories, 1939–1946 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Law School Committee Reports, 1932–1943 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Guest book for the Chancellor’s residence, 1941 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Report, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - articles in the Vanderbilt Alumnus September Vol. 30, no. 8, 1945 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Report on the JUL (Joint University Libraries), 1948 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Academic/Professional Career – Vanderbilt University, 1935-1946
    - Report of the JUL (Joint University Libraries), 1959 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Programs, 1963 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Report on the M.A. in Teaching program at Vanderbilt and Peabody (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Research notes for speeches, 1928-1944 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Research notes for speeches, 1928-1944 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Research notes for speeches, 1928–1944 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Research notes for speeches, 1928–1944 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Research notes for speeches, 1928–1944 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Research notes for speeches, 1928–1944 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Research notes for speeches, 1928–1944 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Research notes for speeches, 1928-1944 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Research notes for speeches, 1928-1944 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Academic/Professional Career – Carnegie Foundation – President, 1946–1953
    - 1940-1963 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Meetings, June – October 1953 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Meetings, November 1953 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Meetings, February – April 1954 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Meetings, October 1954 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Meetings, November 1954 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Meetings, January – July 1955 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Meetings, October – November 1955 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Program – 50th Anniversary, November 1955 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Meetings, January – July 1956 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Meetings, November 1956 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Annual Report, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Annual Report, 1955–1956 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Annual Report, 1955-1956 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Annual Report – 1957–1958 reprint of “The Education of Teachers” (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Official lists of the Board of Trustees, 1954–1956 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Program, 1960 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Academic/Professional Career – State University of New York, (1948–1953)
    - Programs, newsletters, brochures, 1948-1951 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Report of the Board, 1951 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Administrative Papers, 1952 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Report – tuition and fees, 1952 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report of the Board of Trustees, 1953 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - 6th Annual Report Board of Trustees, 1953 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Annual Report of the President, 1953 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Investment review, 1953 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Address by William Carlson, President, 1953 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Annual Report of the Board of Trustees, 1955 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Administrative papers, 1956–1958 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Reports, 1959–1960 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Press release and other papers, 1960-1963 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Program for the inauguration of Dr. Samuel B. Gould, 1965 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Cornell University report, n.d (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Academic/ Professional Career – University of Alabama, President, 1953–1956
    - University related documents, 1944-1953 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Report of the President for the years, 1952–1953 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Notes, 1953 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Press release /newspaper clippings, 1953 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - President’s home – Gorgas House (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Inventory records – President’s mansion (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Campus map, c. 1953 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Resolution re: gift of Dr. Lawrence Reynolds, June 1953 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Library News, 1953 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - “Capstone’s first Lady Displays Charm, Trust” in University of Alabama Alumni Bulletin, Vol. 8, no. 1, April 1954 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Excerpt from Board of Trust meeting, May 29, 1954 re: Supreme Court decision on segregation (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Report of the Faculty October 1954: “ University of Alabama in World Affairs” (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Report December 1954: “University of Alabama in World Affairs” (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Reports, 1954 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Statement to Faculty and Students, February 16, 1956 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Resignation Statement, May 1956 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Editorial by John Wagner in The Mahout, November 1956 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Reports, December 1956 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Reports with appendices, 1956–1959 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - News of the Study and Planning Program, 1957-1958 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Marten ten Hoor, Dean College of Arts and Sciences, 1956-1959 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Joseph Volker, Medical Center, 1961 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - Reports on programs on American Studies, 1962–1963 (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - Programs, brochures, bulletins (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - Academic/Professional Career – President, University of Alabama – Correspondence – Autherine Lucy case – 1956 (photocopies)
    - Statement by University Board of Trust (1956) to exclude Autherine Lucy (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Student suspensions (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Autherine Lucy case – Outgoing correspondence
    - Outgoing correspondence, February 21; March 6, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Outgoing correspondence, March 7; March 14, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Outgoing correspondence, March 16; March 19, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Outgoing correspondence, March 20; April 3, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Outgoing correspondence, April 4; April 6, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Outgoing correspondence, April 7; July 24, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Autherine Lucy case – Incoming correspondence
    - Adams – Ashdown (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Asher – Avery (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Bailey – Barron (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Barton – Bayer (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Beach – Berg (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Biggam – Boydston (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Brandon – Brewton (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Broekhoff – Buchanan (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Budd – Byrne (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Cabeen – Carmichael (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Chalker – Clifton (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - Clopton – Conners (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Cornelius – Cowling (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Craddock – Curving (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Darden – Deloit (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - DePalma – Deleme (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Dickson – Downe (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Drom – Dye (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - Edenfield – Eggman (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - Elhi – Elias (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - Ellis – Everett (Box 51, Folder 29)
    - Faricy – Firestone (Box 51, Folder 30)
    - Fleming – Fuller (Box 51, Folder 31)
    - Garrett – Gutbery (Box 51, Folder 32)
    - Hafner – Hartley (Box 51, Folder 33)
    - Harvey – Hitler (Box 51, Folder 34)
  - Academic/Professional Career – President, University of Alabama – Incoming Correspondence – Autherine Lucy case – 1956 (photocopies)
    - Hogan – Hynard (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Ingalls – Irvin (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Jaffe – Jordan (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Kabacoff – Kent (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Ketchum – Kramer (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Lambert – Lewis (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Linquist – Lytle (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Mabius – Maxwell (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - McCall – Milton (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Moore – Myers (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Newman – Nolen (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Ogden – Owsley (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Page – Parmely (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Paterson – Peterson (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Phillips – Pitts (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Polhemus – Puckett (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Quinette – Ripper (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Rives – Rush (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Sackett – Scudder (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Seale – Shoemaker (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - Sieber – Smith (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Academic/Professional Career – President, University of Alabama – Incoming Correspondence – Autherine Lucy case – 1956 (photocopies)
    - Snellgrove – Stu (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Street – Swope (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Taggart – Tyson (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Ugaldeg – Uiss (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Venable – Vricelle (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Wadsworth – Wiegand (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Williams – Wright (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - X – Z (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Other photocopies of signed incoming correspondence (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Other photocopies of signed incoming correspondence (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - Academic/Professional Career - Learning Resources Institute
    - Planning group on regional cooperation, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - September – November 1959 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - December 1959 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - 1959 - undated (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - January, February 1960 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - March, April 1960 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - May 1960 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - June 1960 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - June 1960 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - July – August 1960 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - September 1960 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - October 1960 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - November 1960 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - December 1960 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - 1960 – undated/misc (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - 1960 – undated misc (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - 1960 – undated misc (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Academic/Professional Career - Learning Resources Institute
    - 1960 – undated/misc (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - 1960 – undated/misc (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - proposed television course, January 1961 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - February 1961 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - March – April 1961 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - May 1961 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - May 1961 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - agreement with CBS, May 1961 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - June 1961 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - July – August 1961-courses and expenses (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - September 1961 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - October 1961 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - November 1961 (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - 1961 (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - “The American Economy” – television course (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - Academic / Professional Career - Learning Resources Institute
    - “The American Economy” – television course (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - “The American Economy” – television course (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - January – March 1962 – expenditures, budgets, grants (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - April 1962 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - May – August 1962 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - September – October 1962 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - November 1962 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - December 1962 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - 1962 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - January – March 1963 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - May – August 1963 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - November 1963 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - 1964 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - 1964-1965 – Financial statements (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Biology course outline (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Course outlines (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - LRI booklet, other material (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Academic/Professional Career – Senior Consultant – Southern Methodist University
    - Class of 1960 – data (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - questionnaire and data, 1961 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - retention data and class profiles, 1961 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - June 1962 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - September 1962 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - October 1 -16, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - October 17, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - October 18 – 30, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - November 1962 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - December 1 -14, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - December 15 -17, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - December 18 – 31, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - December 1962 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Academic/Professional Career – Senior Consultant – Southern Methodist University
    - class data, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Committee Reports and pamphlets, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - reports, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - reports, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - January 1 – 7, 1963 – reports and papers (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - January 7 – 31, 1963 – reports and papers (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - January 1963 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - February 1963 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - March 1963 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - March – April 1963 – Stanford Review; Mustang magazine of SMU (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - April 20, 1963 – Master Plan of Southern Methodist University (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - April 20, 1963 – Master Plan of Southern Methodist University (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - April 27, 1963 – Memo to the Faculty by Willis M. Tate (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Academic/Professional Career – Senior Consultant – Southern Methodist University
    - Report on Scholarships, April 1963 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Reports, April 1963 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Report of the Student Master Plan Committee, April 1963 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Report of the Task Force on Student Life and other papers, April 1963 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Final report of the Task Force on Graduate Education, April 1963 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Report on University Admissions, April 1963 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Jesse Hobson – Master Plan Coordinator, May 1963 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - July 1963 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - confidential memo from Jesse Hobson, October 1963 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Papers by Jesse Hobson (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - July 1965 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - September 1965 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Master Plan – undated (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Master Plan development – undated (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Master Plan development, undated (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Master Plan – background planning (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Master Plan – reports – undated (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Master Plan – reports, undated (Box 59, Folder 18)
- Activities and organizations – Boards
  - American Council on Education
    - Amended Constitution, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - May-July 1953 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - September 1953 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - October 1953 (1) (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - October 1953 (2) (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - November 1953 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - December 1953 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - January 1954 (1) (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - January 1954 (2) (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - February 1954 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - March 1954 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - April 1954 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - May 1954 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - June-July 1954 (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - September 1954 (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - October 1954 (1) (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - October 1954 (2) (Box 60, Folder 17)
  - American Council on Education
    - October 1954 (3) (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - October 1954 (4) (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - November-December 1954 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Committees and Commissions, 1954 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Enrollment Forecast for the State of Washington, 1954 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - January 1955 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - February - March 1955 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - April 1955 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - May 1955 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - June 1955 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - July 1955 (1) (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - July 1955(2) (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - August 1955 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - September 1955 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - October 1955 (1) (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - American Council on Education
    - October 1955 (2) (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - November 1955 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - December 1955 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Washington Enrollment Data, 1955 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous/No Month, 1955 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - January 1956 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - February 1956 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - March-April 1956 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - May 1956 (1) (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - May 1956 (2) (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - June-July 1956 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - August 1956 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - September-October 1956 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - Annual Report Documents, 1956 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - February-March 1957 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - May-June 1957 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - September-October 1957 (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - American Council on Education
    - Miscellaneous/No Month, 1957 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - February 1958 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - March-April 1958 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - April-June 1958 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - October 1958 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - November 1958 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - December 1958 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous/No Month, 1958 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - January 1959 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - February 1959 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - March 1959 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - April 1959 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - April/May 1959 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - May 1959 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - June 1959 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - July 1959 (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - August 1959 (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - September 1959 (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - October 1959 (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - November 1959 (Box 63, Folder 20)
  - American Council on Education
    - December 1959 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - January 1960 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - February 1960 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - March 1960 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - April 1960 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - May 1960 (1) (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - May 1960 (2) (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - June 1960 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - July 1960 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - September 1960 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - October 1960 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - December 1960 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous/No Month, 1960 (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - January 1961 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - March 1961 (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - April-May 1961 (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - June-July 1961 (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - October 1961 (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - January 1962 (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - July-August 1962 (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - October 1962 (1) (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - October 1962 (2) (Box 64, Folder 22)
  - American Council on Education
    - Newsletters, January-February 1963 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Newsletters, March-April 1963 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Newsletters, May-June 1963 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Newsletters, July-August 1963 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Newsletters, September-October 1963 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Newsletters, November 1963 – May 1964 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Booklets and Annual Meeting Documents, 1962-1964 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous/No Date (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous/No Date (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous/No Date (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Board of Foreign Scholarships of the U.S. State Department
    - By-Laws, 1949 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Reports – recipients of awards under public law, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Meeting minutes, 1954-1955 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Reports, 1954 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Reports, 1954 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Reports, 1954 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Department of State International Educational Exchange Service, 1954-1956 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Policy statements, 1955 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Reports, 1955 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Reports, 1955 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - 1955–1956 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Board of Foreign Scholarships of the U.S. State Department
    - Reports, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Meeting agenda and reports, September - December 1956 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Meeting -1956 (1) (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Meeting – 1956 (2) (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Meeting – 1956 (3) (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Meeting – 1956 (4) (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Meeting – 1956 (5) (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Meeting – 1956 (6) (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - 1957–1958 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Meeting minutes, 1961 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - South Africa (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Booklets, pamphlets, brochures (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Commission on Goals for Higher Education in the South
    - Staff papers (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Staff papers (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Statements and reports (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Governor’s Commission on education (Box 68, Folder 4)